<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Frisco Real Estate Podcast with Amy and Kevin Smits</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Smits Team - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Amy and Kevin Smits</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-12-14 16:21:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Amy and Kevin Smits</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Info@TheSmitsTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Frisco Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Smits Team - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lets Get Started on Your 2019 Health Resolutions</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lets-get-started-on-your-2019-health.html</link>
        
          <category>New Year</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-11 12:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+fitness.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The new year is here and I’m sure many of you have made resolutions for getting in better shape. Here are some places in the area where you can get started on accomplishing your health goals this year.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


First, I want to wish you all a happy new year and thank you for your support in 2018. With more than 50% of people saying they want to get healthier in 2019, I thought we’d start the year off by sharing some of the different rec centers, Pilates studios, CrossFit gyms, and all the different places you can get in shape this year.

As you can see in the video above, there are no shortage of options in the area. Next time you’re in the mountains, you might want to check one of the fantastic rec centers out in Breckenridge or Silverthorne.

In the meantime, if you have any questions about real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+fitness.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+fitness.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The new year is here and I’m sure many of you have made resolutions for getting in better shape. Here are some places in the area where you can get started on accomplishing your health goals this year.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The new year is here and I’m sure many of you have made resolutions for getting in better shape. Here are some places in the area where you can get started on accomplishing your health goals this year.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Things Have Changed Lately in Our Local Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-things-have-changed-lately-in-our.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-22 11:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market has been undergoing a lot of changes lately, and so today we’d like to share a quick update on what this recent activity may mean for you and your goals.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


It has been a great time of change here in the mountains as of late, and our real estate market is no exception.

We are seeing new properties listed every day. If you’re thinking of buying or selling, know that now is a fantastic time to do so. Things are moving fast in our local market, and our team would be happy to help you take advantage of this current activity.

Whether you’re looking for the perfect home, are ready to sell, or have questions about your current property’s value, we have what it takes to guide you to your goals.

If you have any questions about buying or selling your home in this market, please feel free to call or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our market has been undergoing a lot of changes lately, and so today we’d like to share a quick update on what this recent activity may mean for you and your goals.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our market has been undergoing a lot of changes lately, and so today we’d like to share a quick update on what this recent activity may mean for you and your goals.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Who Is the Best Short-Term Property Manager?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-property-manager.html</link>
        
          <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-16 13:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rentals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What property manager or property management company should you task with handling your short-term rental? Allow me to share some insight into this key question.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


Recently someone asked us, “Who is the best short-term property manager?”

Well, the truth is that we could not name just one. There are a few different companies we work with that have different rental numbers in different areas. So if you are thinking of hiring someone to manage your short-term rental property, please reach out so we can have a discussion about who would be the best fit for your needs.

“THERE ARE A VARIETY OF DIFFERENT PROPERTY MANAGEMENT COMPANIES OUT THERE THAT OFFER A VARIETY OF SERVICES.”

With that said, many people choose to manage their short-term rental property on their own using Airbnb or VRBO (vacation rental by owner). There are also companies that will help you with bookings and cleaning, while leaving the rest up to you. If you are going this route, we would love to help you out by having our photographer create a 3D virtual tour of your property.

The reality is that there are a variety of different property management companies out there that offer a variety of services. It all comes down to your personal preference.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like a list of some great local property management companies, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rentals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Rentals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What property manager or property management company should you task with handling your short-term rental? Allow me to share some insight into this key question.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What property manager or property management company should you task with handling your short-term rental? Allow me to share some insight into this key question.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Agents Are Important Even if Youre Selling Your Own Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-update-on-frisco-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-21 14:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+why+use+a+real+estate+agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As spring turns to summer, the market is starting to heat up. Now is a great time to get a jump on the market if you’ve been thinking of buying a home.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


It is a beautiful spring here in Frisco and we’re enjoying some lovely weather in the mountains. If you are thinking about visiting, this is a great time to come up. Today we are going to talk about why you need a real estate agent even in a hot seller’s market like this and even if you are selling your home on your own.

Over the last few weeks, I have been hearing from buyers and sellers who want to know about the For Sale By Owner (FSBO) market. Here are a few recent stories I can share.

First, we just listed a home for someone who wasn’t having much success selling her home FSBO. We had to adjust the price down a little bit, we got professional photos taken, and got the word out to a lot of people either in the area or looking for a home in the area. The property received a full-priced offer in just two weeks. The seller was very excited and is looking forward to closing in the next few weeks.

The next story is of a couple who were trying to sell on their own and they put a very small sign attached to their mailbox. I was showing property in the neighborhood and I gave them a call because I thought one of my buyers might be interested in the home. I told them I wasn’t trying to persuade them to list their home with me, but they proceeded to tell me just how horrible their experience was. They were fielding calls at all hours and they needed help. I ended up listing the home, brought the perfect buyer in, and got the title work, surveys, and disclosures covered.

“WE STILL HAVE SOME GREAT INVENTORY AVAILABLE HERE IN FRISCO.”

The main takeaway here is that buyers don’t want to work directly with FSBO sellers. That is why we want to help. If you have seen a FSBO home in the area and you are interested in it, we can provide some insight into the property and maybe even the sellers themselves. We try to find all the FSBO sellers out there and get their information for all of our buyers.

Location is just part of the equation when it comes to selling a home. It is also very important to market the property correctly and provide the most accurate information to buyers in order to make the process as smooth as can be.

Check out the links below for specific details on each area:

• Avon
   • Breckenridge
   • Dillon
   • Edwards
   • Frisco
   • Silverthorne
   • Vail

We still have some great inventory here in Frisco, so it is a great time to come look at homes if you have been thinking about it. If you have any questions about the market or need any help, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+why+use+a+real+estate+agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/2018/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+why+use+a+real+estate+agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As spring turns to summer, the market is starting to heat up. Now is a great time to get a jump on the market if you’ve been thinking of buying a home.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As spring turns to summer, the market is starting to heat up. Now is a great time to get a jump on the market if you’ve been thinking of buying a home.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buyers and Sellers: Take Action Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/its-time-to-get-off-fence.html</link>
        
          <category>Expert Advice</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-04 13:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+It%E2%80%99s+time+to+get+off+the+fence.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re on the fence about buying or selling a home, now is the time to hop off and take action.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, now is a great time. For sellers, there is so little inventory that homes which are priced correctly are selling quickly. We’re seeing multiple offers in the first couple weeks for nearly every home that is selling.

Once the slopes close, however, we are going to see an increase in inventory. One of our listing clients was bringing their townhome onto the market. The last sale was at $650,000 and we were going to price theirs below that because the location was not quite as desirable. But someone in the building decided they needed to sell fast, so they came on at $500,000, which affected everyone in the building. A home that we would have brought on over $600,000 now needs to wait until the prices recover. Granted, they did have multiple offers, and we don’t know how much it sold for, but once it closes, it will definitely have an effect on everyone.

If you’re thinking about selling, let’s price it right to sell quickly.

As interest rates increase, buying power for some buyers decreases. Buyers are going to see an uptick in inventory, but there are still a lot of buyers out there and the competition is fierce. When a property that is a perfect fit for you comes on the market, we need to be ready. If you’re getting a loan, get pre-qualified as soon as possible. We also need to know how to write the contract so that you’re going to win.

“AS INTEREST RATES INCREASE, BUYING POWER FOR SOME BUYERS DECREASES.”

If you’re thinking about buying, remember that interest rates are on the rise.

For every $100,000 of purchasing power, when the interest rates go up by 1%, the cost of that is approximately $60 per $100,000. I’m not a lender, so I can’t give you an exact figure, but you can check out a mortgage calculator online to see how rising rates will affect you personally.

There are going to be some great properties coming onto the market, so let’s be ready.

If you have any questions or need any help, please feel free to contact us. We would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+It%E2%80%99s+time+to+get+off+the+fence.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+It%E2%80%99s+time+to+get+off+the+fence.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re on the fence about buying or selling a home, now is the time to hop off and take action.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re on the fence about buying or selling a home, now is the time to hop off and take action.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect From the 2018 Summit County Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018-summit-county-market-predictions.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Predictions</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-18 10:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+2018+Summit+County+market+predictions.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What can you expect from the Summit Country real estate market in 2018? I’ll share a few of my predictions, as well as an announcement about my new video series.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


What will the 2018 real estate market look like? We’ll share a few predictions. I’m also excited to announce a new video series.

As many of you know, homes were selling extremely fast in 2017. Inventory continued to be low, and 25% of homes were selling in less than two weeks.

In 2018, we don’t expect that to change. We think that 30% of homes will sell in less than two weeks, and we will continue to have a shortage of inventory.

“THE MARKET CONTINUES TO IMPROVE, AND HOMES ARE SELLING QUICKLY.”

If you are looking to buy a home this year, you need to be in touch with us. Our buyer agents will look for a home that suits your specific needs.

If you are thinking of selling, there couldn’t be a better time. The market continues to improve, and homes are selling quickly.

I also want to let you know that this year, we will introduce you to a new company in Summit County each week. We will interview them to find out what they do and see what specials they offer you. We’ll also introduce you to businesses in Vail and Beaver Creek.

If you have any questions in the meantime, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+2018+Summit+County+market+predictions.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+2018+Summit+County+market+predictions.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What can you expect from the Summit Country real estate market in 2018? I’ll share a few of my predictions, as well as an announcement about my new video series.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What can you expect from the Summit Country real estate market in 2018? I’ll share a few of my predictions, as well as an announcement about my new video series.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tax Reform and Real Estate: Whats Changing?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tax-bill-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Tax Plan</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-10 12:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+How+will+the+tax+reform+bill+affect+real+estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How will tax changes impact the real estate market? Here are a few things we’re keeping an eye on.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


A lot of you have been asking me lately about the tax reform bill and how it will affect the real estate market. Since the majority of homeowners around here are secondary homeowners, it won’t have the same effect on their vacation homes as it will on their primary residences. However, there are a few changes that may affect you that I wanted to touch on today.

First things first—the mortgage interest deduction cap has been decreased from $1 million to $750,000. Since 60% of homeowners around here finance their homes, it will have an impact.

Another part of this tax bill is the limiting of state and local tax deductions. Here in Colorado, our taxes are already so low that it won’t have a big impact. However, for those of you in states where the taxes are much higher, you’ll definitely want to do some homework to see how it will affect your primary and secondary residences.

“CAPITAL GAINS WEREN’T TOUCHED IN THE NEW PLAN.”

Finally, the capital gains tax is another piece that a lot of people are worried about. Basically, if you’ve lived in a home for two out of the last five years as a primary residence, you can deduct any capital gains up to $250,000 as a single person and up to $500,000 as a married couple. This piece wasn’t touched in the tax plan, which is good news for homeowners.

Click here for a deeper look at the tax reform bill.

If you have any more questions about exactly how these changes are going to affect you personally, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+How+will+the+tax+reform+bill+affect+real+estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+How+will+the+tax+reform+bill+affect+real+estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How will tax changes impact the real estate market? Here are a few things we’re keeping an eye on.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How will tax changes impact the real estate market? Here are a few things we’re keeping an eye on.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How a New Refinancing Program Could Help You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/this-new-program-allows-you-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-21 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent++This+new+program+allows+you+to+refinance+quickly.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Doug Sullivan has developed a new program that allows cash buyers to refinance quickly.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


Today I’m going to introduce Doug Sullivan, one of our lenders who has a new product that is really great for people who are purchasing a home with cash and would like to cash out. Typically that takes several months, but thanks to Doug, there is a new program available.

His mortgage tip comes with regards to delayed financing.

Standard mortgage guidelines for doing a cash-out refinance require the homeowner to wait six months after they close, but he has a program that allows people to do that right away.

“STANDARD MORTGAGE GUIDELINES FOR DOING A CASH-OUT REFINANCE REQUIRE THE HOMEOWNER TO WAIT SIX MONTHS AFTER THEY CLOSE.”

There are a couple examples of how this helped past clients of his:

For the first example, he had a client who was wanting a loan but was in a position to pay cash. What they did was write the contract as cash. The reason for this is that they were competing with a lot of other offers, and that allowed the seller to take their contract because of the cash position and the fact that they could close within two weeks. After they closed, Doug applied the mortgage, and within 30 days they had the financing that they wanted.

The second example was a client who was interested in a property that was not habitable by lending terms because there was a plumbing issue. So they paid cash, closed, did the repair, and then we did our financing and got them in place 45 days after closing—they took advantage of today’s low rates.

If you have questions about this program or any other mortgage program, please give us a call. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent++This+new+program+allows+you+to+refinance+quickly.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent++This+new+program+allows+you+to+refinance+quickly.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Doug Sullivan has developed a new program that allows cash buyers to refinance quickly.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Doug Sullivan has developed a new program that allows cash buyers to refinance quickly.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your New Resort Real Estate Experts</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-new-resort-real-estate-experts.html</link>
        
          <category>Colorado Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Resort Real Estate Experts</category>
        
          <category>New Venture</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-06 10:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Resort+Real+Estate+Experts.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We are excited to announce our new venture as Resort Real Estate Experts!


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


We’ve been with Century 21 Gold for nearly 10 years, but it was time for a change. We are so excited about our new venture as Resort Real Estate Experts!

Over the next couple of months, we’ll introduce you to a lot of new features on our website. We’ll also have a grand opening at our new office in Edwards, Colorado.

If you’re in town and you see one of our new bright pink open house signs, stop in and say hello.

Plus, if you have any ideas or topics you would like to learn more about in our next video, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Resort+Real+Estate+Experts.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent-+Resort+Real+Estate+Experts.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We are excited to announce our new venture as Resort Real Estate Experts!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We are excited to announce our new venture as Resort Real Estate Experts!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Real Estate Trends in East Vail & Summit County </title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-local-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-16 13:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Your+local+real+estate+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Homes are still selling quickly in East Vail and Summit County, but there are a few changes in the market. We have your full market update today.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


What’s happening in the East Vail and Summit County real estate market?

Properties coming on the market right now have come down a bit in price. Yesterday, there were 31 price reductions. Buyers are ready to buy, but properties need to be priced correctly in order to sell.

That said, homes priced under $500,000 tend to sell in less than a week. Homes between $500,000 and $1 million are selling in under two months. However, homes over $1 million are selling slower, since that is where we have the majority of our inventory. There are also fewer buyers in that price range.

“HOMES PRICED UNDER $500,000 ARE SELLING IN LESS THAN A WEEK!”

If you are thinking of buying or selling a home, reach out to us and make sure that we have your housing criteria set up correctly. Homes are selling quickly, and it’s important that we match your motivation to our motivation. If you want to buy quickly, for example, we want to be able to get in touch with you as soon as possible. If you don’t want to buy for another year or so, we want to check in with you every couple months to touch base.

We also have a couple of exciting new properties that will be on the market. There are two brand-new duplexes that will come on the East Vail market in the next couple of weeks at $2 million. If you are interested, let someone on our team know and we will send you as much information as we can, including 3-D tours.

We also have a couple of condos in the $350,000 price range. Those will sell quickly, so get in touch with us soon if you are interested.

As always, if you have any other real estate questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Your+local+real+estate+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Your+local+real+estate+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Homes are still selling quickly in East Vail and Summit County, but there are a few changes in the market. We have your full market update today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Homes are still selling quickly in East Vail and Summit County, but there are a few changes in the market. We have your full market update today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Fire Is Over in Summit County</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post-fire-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-18 15:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Thank goodness the recent wildfire has been put out. Now things are getting back to normal in Summit County real estate.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


Thank goodness that the winds have shifted and we are finally getting some rain in Summit County. The fire last week was frightening. Anytime you see flames in the mountains, it’s pretty scary.

Although parts of Breckenridge were evacuated, everyone is back home safe now and the fire is out. We were lucky that the winds shifted and the rains came. Thanks to everyone who had a hand in helping control and put out that nasty fire.

“THE WIND HAS SHIFTED.”

As far as the real estate market is concerned, our inventory is finally starting to pick up. The average days on market remains extremely low. If you’re looking to buy a home up here, give us a call, text, or email now so we can start aggressively searching for a home for you. Even if you’re out of town, we can FaceTime or Skype you in to take a look at any homes. There are quite a few that have recently come on the market.

If you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Thank goodness the recent wildfire has been put out. Now things are getting back to normal in Summit County real estate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Thank goodness the recent wildfire has been put out. Now things are getting back to normal in Summit County real estate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Buying Season Is Officially Underway</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/colorado-resorts-real-estate-agent-many_78.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Amy and Kevin Smits</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-11 15:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kevin+%26+Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Act+now+to+save+thousands.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With the ski season over, tons of properties are flooding the market. Here’s why you need to act quickly in order to take advantage.


Buying a home? Click here to perform a full home search
Selling a home? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Call me at 970-418-0183 for a FREE home buying or selling consultation


Although the question of when the best time to buy is a complex question, I’ve got some information to share with you today that shows why May and June specifically are good times to buy a home in this market.

The ski season is mostly over now, which means we are going to start to see homes come off of the rental market and into the purchasing market. Inventory is finally increasing for home buyers, giving them many more options than they had just a few months ago. Interest rates are continuing to stay fairly low as well, and with fewer rentals it is much easier to see properties.

If you were here in the winter and wanted to see properties, it was probably difficult for you since so many of them were rented out. Those properties are vacant now, though.

Another reason to act timely if you want to secure a good deal is because once a property sells, the next similar property that comes on the market will be listed for $10,000 or $15,000 more. We recently saw a wilderness condo come on the market for $305,000 and sell within a few days. The next similar condo that came on the market was listed at $320,000. With inventory so low, that’s how quickly prices are going up.

If you’re thinking about buying a home, reach out to us. We can make sure you’re alerted to the properties that match the criteria you are looking for as soon as they come on the market. If you can’t make it out here to see them in person, we can even set you up with a pair of VR goggles so you can take a 3-D home tour. We do these for every one of our listings and if you haven’t taken a VR tour yet, it’s something you need to do. Reach out to us and we’ll send you a pair of goggles.

“We’re happy to send a pair of these VR goggles your way.”

If you have any other questions for us, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kevin+%26+Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Act+now+to+save+thousands.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kevin+%26+Amy+Smits/Colorado+Resorts+Real+Estate+Agent+Act+now+to+save+thousands.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

With the ski season over, tons of properties are flooding the market. Here’s why you need to act quickly in order to take advantage.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Amy and Kevin Smits</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

With the ski season over, tons of properties are flooding the market. Here’s why you need to act quickly in order to take advantage.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Frisco, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Amy and Kevin Smits</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Amy and Kevin Smits</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Smits Team - your professional Frisco Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
